OBJECTIVE

Join a cohesive team of driven artists, developers, and leaders producing user-friendly and convention-challenging designs, interfaces, and experiences; push my creative boundaries, hone my skillset, and mature my career working with inspiring thinkers and creators.

EDUCATION

B.A. New Media

UNC Asheville 2012
Graduated with Distinction
Concentration in 3D Animation

Coursework:

Digital Design Principles
Web & Interface Design
Advanced Animation Techniques
Video Editing & Motion Graphics
Branding & Marketing
Figure Drawing & Concepting
Art & Animation Histories

Training:

- ➤ *Adobe Creative Suite* including graphic design, branding, vector graphics, photo/video editing, digital painting and animation, compositing, UI prototyping and implementation.
- ➤ 3D programs Maya and Zbrush including environment, character and mechanical modeling, texturing, rigging, animation, rendering
- ➤ *Drawing* including figure, industrial, shading and proportion study, character design, concepting, storyboarding, and logo design.
- ➤ *Internship* experience managing website portal updates, social media engagement, email newsletters, and database management for a leadership training non-profit.

SKILLS

Web Development / Interactive

Front-end design using HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JS, Node, and PHP with a focus on visual communication and hiearchy, input paradigms and testing, user-flow & refinement to create unified experiences across legacy and emerging products.

Design of responsive interfaces, web-apps, landing pages, and traditional sites utilizing interactive & assistive UI, cross-platform branding, load optimization, device testing, database integration, analytics, and technical SEO and site-auditing.

Graphic Design & Illustration

From classically inspired, clean vector design to rich cartoon & fantasy illustration; including full branding, typography, color theory and palettes, ad design, iconography, photo-editing, and digital painting.

Design, presentation, and implementation of wireframes, story-boards, mock-ups, and user-flows. Assistive tools, resources, and communications to support both internal and client-side needs, and reporting on analytics, project timelines, and product releases.

Marketing & Testing

Google Analytics Certified, GDN image ad campaigns, email marketing and responsive email coding, A/B landing page testing for CRO, heat/scrollmap analysis, and device testing and profiling for analytics.

3D & Video

3D and VR GUI design, Character sculpting, mechanical modeling, texture painting, and extensive character and facial animation.

Video editing and 2D graphic & text animation, motion tracking, and post compositing.

TECH

Development:

Linux: Ubuntu, Fedora, Arch (Desktop & Server)
MacOS, Windows
HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Bash
JS, NodeJS & Npm, JSON, ES2015
Handlebars, Jquery, Express, Phaser
Firefox & Chrome Dev Tools
Apache, SSH, SFTP, SFTP, SSL, AWS
Git, Subversion
Android and iOS testing

Design & Animation:

Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign InvisionApp, Sketch, Draw.io, Gliffy After Effects, Premiere, Final Cut Unity3D, Maya, Modo, Zbrush Ableton Live, Logic Pro

Marketing & Testing:

Google Analytics Certified Adwords, Tag Manager, Google Search Console Campaign Monitor, Mailchimp Salesforce, Hubspot, Insightly Visual Website Optimizer CrazyEgg, Mouseflow

Project Management:

Slack, Jira, Trello, Asana MS, Libre, & Open Offices Zoom API Lightroom

EXPERIENCE

Designer, Front-End Developer, Animator

Mursion

May 2016 - Present

Manage visual design, implementation, and best practices for a variety of products including mobile, web, and native software for clients and leads. Ongoing work developing a cohesive portal and interactive analytics viewer for session scheduling/matchmaking, simulation design and launch, system verification for hardware compatibility testing, resource materials, and visual metrics and recordings browser.

Work with the software dev team to design visual assets for proprietary technologies, as well as provide responsive web front-ends for a variety of client and internal uses. Led the re-design of the company website in the fall of 2016 and manage ongoing updates & support. Consult with the sales team for new lead generation, SEO, analytics, CRM, both internal and external facing email communication, and marketing assets.

Additionally, support the animation pipeline providing character idles, gestures, and facials for 3D adult and child avatars, and weight paint new characters. Pose, clean, and embelish mocap animations in Motion Builder and Maya and test & tweak in game within Unity 3D. Work closely with the character artists and interactors for input on rigging, blend shapes, facial animation, and body language communication, and QA team for technical changes and bug fixes.

Internet Marketing Designer/Developer

Element-360

September 2014 - May 2016

In charge of all visual development and programming including image & HTML5 ad creation, refining site performance with A/B testing and heatmap/behaviour analysis, and technical SEO auditing.

Extensive experience in Wordpress with close to 100 websites for 40+ real estate communities from around the country involving site speed recommendations, behaviour flow research, tracking code implementation, site updates, and sitemaps. Work within diverse brand guidelines to design sites and landing pages for lead generation, complementary ads (based on Adwords PPC text-ad performance), and responsive email newsletters.

EXPERIENCE

(continued)

Freelance

- ➤ *UI/UX Design* During a two-month contract designed and prototyped an IOT app authoring web-application. With a small team, outlined the scope of the app's services, planned the implementation of the single-page front end, storyboarded the user flow, and created visual assets.
- ➤ Website Development Multiple portfolio websites created to show-case professional work and services with custom, responsive WP themes while providing general CMS training, SEO, and ongoing updates.
- ➤ *Design* Logo rework for a startup mobile app, and 3D modeling for 3D printing for a local law firm.

Game Designer, Illustrator, Animator, & Video Editor The Littlest Golfer, Inc.

April 2013 - August 2014

Game designer and lead artist for 2D mobile game Bunker Blast created in Unity3D and sold on the App Store and Google Play. Created the UI, static art assets, character animations in photoshop spritesheets for Unity3D, designed puzzle-based levels, and image ads for the game release.

Additionally, worked in small team to create a 3D Animated Pilot children's show. Designed, modeled, rigged, and animated characters, handled all editing, compositing, and credits within After Effects, and created promotional print materials for the show premiere.

Designer, Web Tech, Social Media Manager Internship

Leadership Asheville

August 2012 - December 2012

Managed web site maintenance for an active portal used by over 80 participants of an annual leadership training course.

In addition, created event stationary and promo prints for fundraisers, designed seasonal event newsletters, promoted events on social media, and managed online donation records and contact database.

REFERENCES

Chad Martin - Element-360 | *President*

► chad@element-360.com

Claudette Silver - Silver Muse Productions | *Owner*

claudette@silvermuse.net

Christopher Oakley - UNC Asheville | *Tenured Animation Professor & Mentor*

➤ coakley@unca.edu

Matt Shanor - The Littlest Golfer, Inc. | *Art Director*

mattshanor@gmail.com

INFO

NGPFontaine@protonmail.com 828 719 2374

79B Hill St. **San Francisco, CA 94110**

nicfontaine.com
github.com/ngpfontaine